<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A reply, to a namelesse pamphlet, intituled, An answer to a speech without doors, &amp;c. Or, a defence of Master Chaloner's speech. Wherein the question is rightly stated, the interest of the kingdome and Parliament vindicated, and all moderate men answered. / By G.G. a lover of his countrey. Published according to order.</title>
            <author>G. G.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1646</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 16 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A85742</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing G21</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E362_26</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R201222</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99861754</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99861754</idno>
            <idno type="VID">113898</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A85742)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 113898)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 58:E362[26])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A reply, to a namelesse pamphlet, intituled, An answer to a speech without doors, &amp;c. Or, a defence of Master Chaloner's speech. Wherein the question is rightly stated, the interest of the kingdome and Parliament vindicated, and all moderate men answered. / By G.G. a lover of his countrey. Published according to order.</title>
                  <author>G. G.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 6 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for R. Leybourn,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1646.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>A reply to: Birkenhead, Sir John. An answer to a speech without doores (Wing B2960).</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "Nou: 23".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Chaloner, Thomas, 1595-1661.</term>
               <term>Birkenhead, John, --  Sir, 1616-1679. --  Answer to a speech without doores.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1642-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Scotland --  Politics and government --  1625-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-09</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-03</date>
            <label>Geremy Carnes</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-03</date>
            <label>Geremy Carnes</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:113898:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p> A REPLY, TO A Nameleſſe PAMPHLET, Intituled, <hi>An Anſwer to a Speech without doors, &amp;c.</hi> OR, A DEFENCE OF Maſter <hi>CHALONER'S</hi> Speech.</p>
            <p>WHEREIN The Queſtion is rightly ſtated, The Intereſt of the Kingdome and Parliament vindicated, And all moderate men anſwered.</p>
            <p>By <hi>G. G</hi> a lover of his Countrey.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Veritas Index ſui &amp; obliqui.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Publiſhed according to Order.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>R. Leybourn</hi> 1646.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:113898:2"/>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:113898:2"/>
            <head>A Reply to a nameleſſe Pamphlet, intituled an Anſwer <hi>To a Speech without Doores, &amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg> Had thought M. <hi>Chaloners</hi> ſpeech ſhould not ſooner have been publiſhed then received, the joy of our Nation for ſo knowing a man of it, his gallant ſayings did not tend to the advance of himſelf, but his Countrey, not to deſtroy the King (as ſome will have it) but to let him know hee was Prince of a People that know their priviledges, and his juſt autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity, which they would not have queſtioned by ſervants and hirelings, but preſerved by Freemen and Maſters: but the bad people of our Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, that had rather be ſlaves to ſtrangers, then live in neceſſary ſubjection under the Government of their Countrymen, muſt ſtretch their little proportion of wit to a defence of the Scoriſhmens intereſt in the diſpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſition of the Engliſh affairs. For allow them a right in the diſpoſall of the King in <hi>England,</hi> and that of the Kingdom muſt needs follow: but the undertaker of this muſt be ſuch anone whoſe expreſſions of himſelfe in Greek may perſwade a man of the excellency of the Engliſh intended to put a Blur on this Worthy of <hi>Iſrael:</hi> But to leave this prefacing (as he terms it) I ſhall diſcover the weakneſſe of this Malignant imagined confutation.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:113898:3"/>
            <p> And firſt (God not permitting him in this to lye) he admires Maſter <hi>Chaloner</hi> comming forth as a <hi>Goliah,</hi> and being unable to meet him in the field of <hi>Truth,</hi> which M. <hi>Chaloner</hi> had ſtated in few lines (making the Scotchmans much appear little, which are whereſoever the King of <hi>Scotland</hi> hath an intereſt in their King they may diſpoſe of him.</p>
            <q>But the Kingdom of <hi>Scotland</hi> hath an intereſt in their King, hee being in <hi>England,</hi> therefore in <hi>England</hi> they may diſpoſe of him.</q>
            <p>But he will have it altered from the Truth, and ſayth, thus it ought to be.</p>
            <q>
               <p>Whatſoever is by Covenant, Treaty, and the very Law of Nations of joynt intereſt, and common concernment to both Kingdoms, ought not to be diſpoſed of, but by mutuall adviſe of both Kingdoms for the good of both.</p>
               <p>But the perſon of the King, whether in <hi>England</hi> or <hi>Scotland,</hi> is by Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venant, Treaty, and the very law of Nations, of joynt intereſt, and common concernment to both Kingdoms.</p>
               <p>Therefore the perſon of the King whether in <hi>England</hi> or <hi>Scotland</hi> ought not be be diſpoſed of, but by the mutuall adviſe of both Kingdoms, for the good of both.</p>
            </q>
            <p>I confeſſe, for a principle for him to ground his argument on thus. It ought to be, But whereas he urges Covenant, Treaty, and the Law of Nations to be the ground the Scots work upon to prove their intereſt in the diſpoſing of the perſon of the King he being in <hi>England,</hi> if it were as well proved, as it is by him urged, it might appear rationall, but not true enough for rationall Engliſhmen to believe it. For as no preſident can be brought to prove the King of <hi>England</hi> was ever in his Kingdom of <hi>England</hi> diſpoſed of by the greateſt forreigne Prince, I hope wee are not grown ſo effeminate to let him be diſpoſed of, or we ſubjected by one of the meaneſt people.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Page</hi> 3, he ſayth the Scotch Papers do ſtate the queſtion not upon the authority, power and office of the King, but upon the perſon of the King.</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:113898:3"/>
            <p> When a queſtion is put to have judgement given on it, if it be not right put, it cannot be rightly judged: And the caſe between us and the Scots is not how it is put, but how it ought to be.</p>
            <p>He hath an ill tongue that cannot tell a good tale for himſelf, the Scots make the perſon of the King the only thing of diſpute, but wee are by Covenant oblieged to mayntayn as well the Law of the Land, as the perſon of the King, therefore they leaving that out hath made the caſe imperfect.</p>
            <p>But imagine the perſon of the King to be the only thing now in di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpute, yet hath the Parliament of <hi>England</hi> the ſole diſpoſing of it in <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The caſe is thus, both the Kingdomes have voted, the Kings perſon ought to be diſpoſed of, and therefore it ought, to be ſo beyond diſpute; ſo that now the queſtion is whether the Parliament of <hi>England</hi> ſhall diſpoſe of him in <hi>England,</hi> or the Scots and Parliament. Now as it is a great prejudice to the honour of the Engliſh Nation to have any other people to diſpoſe of their King in their own Country ſingly, or joyntly, ſo it ought to be looked into whether they have a right to do it, if they have a right, it muſt be by cuſtome, or an Act of Parliament: And if they can ſhew neither Preſident nor Law, God forbid that the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment that ſitteth to make us free, and preſerve the priviledge of the En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gliſh Nation ſhould conſent to this that will ſo much deſtroy it.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Page</hi> 3, he alſo ſayth, That the honour, perſon, and juſt priviledges of the King ought by Covenant to be mayntained, wherefore they be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing joyned in it, they are bound to mayntain it.</p>
            <p>We will allow that they ought, and when they finde that the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament doth take away the juſt priviledges, or wrong his perſon, then let them endevour to defend it: and if the Parliament cannot ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtifie their actions by their priviledges they will be blameable.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Page</hi> 4, he ſayth, the paper ſayth, <hi>Perſona ſequitur locum,</hi> and his per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon muſt be diſpoſed of by the ſupreme power of that Countrey where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever he ſhall hap to abide. By which principle ſayth he, the perſon of the King of <hi>England,</hi> if he were in <hi>Scotland</hi> muſt be diſpoſed of by the ſupream power of that Countrey: And was not this well pleaded for the intereſt of the Parliament of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>There is nothing can be ſayd to juſtifie the juſt ſpirit of M. <hi>Chaloner</hi> more then this noble expreſſion, for as hee would have no inchroach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment on the priviledge of the Engliſh Nation by the Scots, ſo he is equal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:113898:4"/> juſt in defending the priviledges of the Scots againſt the Engliſh.</p>
            <p>He ſayth in <hi>Page</hi> 9 of M. <hi>Chalenors</hi> Speech, he reades that what per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſoever commeth into the Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> hee is forthwith a ſubject of <hi>England,</hi> for being protected by the Laws, hee becomes ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject to the Laws. On which hee concludeth that when an Embaſſadour comming from an other Countrey into <hi>England,</hi> can receive no prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction in <hi>England,</hi> and further inferres that the honour of the Parliament and Kingdome are blemiſhed by this with forreigners.</p>
            <p>As the Laws of all Nations are made poſitive to all people reſiding under the protection of them without exception of Embaſſadours, yet the condition of Embaſſadours is ſo welcome to a Kingdom or Common wealth (that always comming to make peace, or continue it) that they have from the beginning had the priviledge to be protected in all Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treys where they ſhall happen to be, and our Laws of <hi>England</hi> are ſo agreeable to the Civill Law, that the ſubjection an Embaſſadour is in by them, is agreeable to that Law of Nations that maintaineth their freedome, wherefore although they are not excepted from it, yet are they not liable to prejudice by it, therefore any reaſonable creature may judge whether the honour of the Kingdom and Parliament can for this be brought in queſtion by Forreigners. This civill protection to Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners or Embaſſadours is in <hi>Scotland</hi> as well as <hi>England,</hi> and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though he will have the contrary, yet will the Parliament of <hi>Englands</hi> Commiſſioners reſiding in <hi>Scotland,</hi> claime as their <hi>Jus,</hi> the ſame pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tection and priviledge there, as they and other Embaſſadours enjoy in <hi>England,</hi> and will beyond all peradventure have it.</p>
            <p>But in <hi>page</hi> 5 on theſe words of Maſter <hi>Chaloners.</hi> That if a King of <hi>Scotland</hi> had come into <hi>England</hi> before the union, his perſon might have been diſpoſed of by the ſole authority of the Laws of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>He inſinuates, that by this principle the Prince of <hi>Wales,</hi> his perſon is to be diſpoſed of by the authority of the Laws of <hi>France,</hi> and the King and Parliament, have no authority to recall him and is not this a good ſalve for the honour of the Parliament? ſayth he.</p>
            <p>This is a further diſcovery of his quibling and little ability to judge on ſuch things for want of knowledge in the proceedings of former ages in ſuch caſes. He needed not have gone further for preſidents then his own Countrey (if he be an Engliſh man) in this caſe, for the taking priſoner of <hi>Richard</hi> the firſt King of <hi>England</hi> by the Duke of <hi>Auſtria,</hi> as he paſſed through his Countrey at his return from the termed Holy
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:113898:4"/> Warre, notwithſtanding they were both ingaged in it, and the ſecuring of the perſon of <hi>Mary</hi> Queen of Scots in the Reigne of Queen <hi>Eliza<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beth.</hi> But if any ſhall ſay they were both enemies to <hi>England,</hi> as well the Queen of Scots as the Duke of <hi>Auſtria,</hi> and therefore to take all ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantages againſt each other. It is moſt ſure that the King of <hi>England</hi> and the Duke of <hi>Auſtria</hi> wereboth in amity and kept good correſpon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dencie, as was neceſſary for Princes whoſe Countreys lay ſo far diſtant one from the other, and the Queen of Scots had ſeverall Ties on the Queen of <hi>England</hi> that might obliege her friendſhip to her, as that of kinred, the leaving out of her Coat the Armes of <hi>England,</hi> which the Kingdom of <hi>France</hi> had adjudged her a right to beare, and aſſurance from the Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi> of her welcome and ſafety in <hi>England,</hi> had ſhee ſtaid in her own Countrey till it came into her hand, and as there was no certain peace, ſo there was no war between them. Wherefore if the Prince of <hi>Wales</hi> is gone into <hi>France,</hi> without aſſurance from that Kingdom of his ſafety there, and liberty to return, he may, for ought I know, have the ſame fortune that theſe Princes had, and as his going was without the conſent of the Parliament, ſo if it ſhould happen he ſhould ſuffer there, they are free from blame of his misfortune.</p>
            <p>A little further he ſayth Maſter <hi>Chaloner</hi> hath it thus. No man can be ſayd to be <hi>Rex</hi> but in <hi>Regno,</hi> wherefore ſayth he, by juſt Analogy the Parliament of <hi>England</hi> cannot be acknowledged a Parliament, but in <hi>England</hi> only, Neyther can there Commiſſioners in any other Kingdom or State being admitted to propound, declare, treat, or conclude in name of both Houſes; Theſe are fine <hi>Oxford</hi> Inferences for as a King of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> by being in <hi>France</hi> loſeth not his Title of King of <hi>England,</hi> he gaineth not the Title of King of <hi>France,</hi> And they may take him as Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject of <hi>France</hi> and King of <hi>England</hi> as we know they have done thoſe Kings as have been Dukes of <hi>Normandy.</hi> And if they will admit the King of <hi>England</hi> his Title of <hi>England,</hi> he being in <hi>France,</hi> Maſter <hi>Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loner</hi> only denying Forreign King, the Title of that Countrey where he ſhall happen to comeunto and not the Title of his own that he brought with him they will admit whom he appoint his Meſſengers or Agents as ſervant of the King of <hi>England,</hi> when they ſhall reſide there from him, and the Parliament when they ſend their Commiſſioners thither, or to any other Countrey, deſireth not the title of the Parliament of that Countrey, nor their Commiſſioners to be ſo accepted: But thoſe that will allow them the title and power of the Parliament of <hi>England</hi> in
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:113898:5"/> 
               <hi>England,</hi> may accept of their Commiſſioners in any other Countrey, as ſervants to the Parliament of <hi>England</hi> without prejudice of the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of that Countrey where their Commiſſioners ſhall ſo reſide. And although in <hi>England</hi> we would not admit of <hi>Mary</hi> as Queen of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> yet was ſhee acknowledged Queen of Scots at her being here.</p>
            <p>A few lines further Maſter <hi>Chalenor,</hi> ſayth he, in his <hi>pag.</hi> 9, telleth us, If the Scots be our fellows why come they not to our Parliaments, on which, ſayth he, if it can be made to appear that they be our fellows, equals and brethren, they may come to our Parliaments and ſee how the priviledges of Parliament is mainteined, doth it make a breach of privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viledge of Parliament to doe juſtice in it? And when the Scots can make it appear that they are in that capacity, that M. <hi>Chalenor</hi> and all the Kingdom knoweth them to want, God forbid but they ſhould have right, and then how could that be againſt the honour of the Parliament?</p>
            <p>On what M. <hi>Chaloner</hi> ſayth of <hi>John</hi> King pf <hi>England,</hi> in his Speech in this Anſwerers <hi>pag.</hi> 6. he will have it much to ſtrengthen the Scotch papers, for ſayth he, if the King of <hi>England</hi> muſt be diſpoſed of by the ſole authority of both Houſes of Parliament, what ſhall become of the perſon of the King of <hi>Scotland?</hi> There is no more cauſe of doubt in them of that, then we ought to make of their diſpoſing of the King of <hi>England,</hi> whom they have in their cuſtody, and as he is in <hi>England</hi> they are unjuſt in deteining him, but if they ſhall get him into <hi>Scotland,</hi> as they have no right in him in <hi>England,</hi> we could pertein as little to him, he being in <hi>Scotland,</hi> and though M. <hi>Chaloner</hi> pleadeth for a ſole power in both Hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes to diſpoſe of him in <hi>England,</hi> yet doth he not plead for it out of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> as their ſuggeſtion will have it, which diſcovers this Anſwer of a falſe calumner, and that he hath an inſight into his diſability to anſwer other mens, and therefore he will make queſtions of his own.</p>
            <p>This pretended Anſwer to M. <hi>Chaloners</hi> Speech is no better then that of this Anſwerers fellow Collegian, where telling a ſheepherd, he was a ſheep and he would prove him ſo, the ſhepherd deſiring to know how, he replyed, That the ſheepherd had a head, and a ſheep had a head, <hi>ergo</hi> he was a ſheep.</p>
            <p>The reſt that commeth from this Subtiliſt is no anſwer, but a mali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious aſperſion on M. <hi>Chaloner,</hi> and the honourable Parliament, and as he endeth ſo do I, with my deſire of God, that from ſuch Apoſtates from their native Country and Countrymen he would deliver us.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
